Rovshen Paltayev

Software Engineer

Ambitious Software Engineer with 5+ years of work experience in developing large-scale front-end and back-end applications with strong data structure, algorithm, and problem-solving fundamentals. Developed complex and user-critical path features with efficient and scalable solutions.

✓ rapaltayev@gmail.com	+18326308632
Austin TX, USA	www.rovshen.com
in linkedin.com/in/rovshenpaltayev	github.com/rpaltayev

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages JAVA | Python | JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS3 Web Spring Boot | React.js | Redux | Node.js |

| SQL | CQL | Technologies | Express.js | REST

 Data
 MySQL | Cassandra | PostgreSQL | Mongo
 Data Modeling
 JSON | XML

Management DB

Big Data AWS | Splunk | Elasticsearch | Zookeeper | Tools Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins

Kafka | New Relic | DataDog | Redis

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Ping Identity

04/2021 - Present Austin TX

Achievements/Tasks

- Played a key role in integrating and releasing newly acquired Identity Orchestration product with PingOne (IDAAS) using technologies like MongoDB, Redis, and Node.js.
- Designed, implemented, and successfully released for GA a flow orchestration service that integrates external APIs with the platform (Web Postman).
- Developed various plugins to integrate existing microservices with flow orchestration and management services.
- Explored and did **POC on graph database Neo4j** to fully remodel the authorization model as document databases were not sufficient for many to many relationships.
- Created and maintained critical stateful and stateless platform services that teams use to integrate features into our product in a CICD microservice architecture.
- Created rich and informative documentation and video presentations for the most complex services on the platform.

Software Engineer

Ping Identity

03/2019 - 04/2021 Austin TX

Achievements/Tasks

- Analyzed authorization model, compiled list of bottlenecks, and outlined use cases to determine bottlenecks in the system. Came up with short-term and long-term solutions.
- Re-designed and implemented permissions (authorization) calculation service increasing **throughput minimum by 50x**, increasing **efficiency minimum 5x**, and **reducing response size by 70x** in worst-case scenarios.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale identity management platform-wide software deployments collaborating across the teams, including testing features and correcting code.
- Helped team members with onboarding and created a variety of resources for future employees decreasing overhead for onboarding.
- Developed microservice-based distributed systems with four g availability, high throughput, fault tolerance, and performance.
- Built highly complex UI web application React components and refactored them to improve overall UI efficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Title/Position

Workplace/Company

Full Stack Engineer

Brighten Technology Solutions

01/2017 - 03/2019 Houston TX

Achievements/Tasks

- Collaborated with an agile team of 6, and helped prioritize and scope feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Built and maintained web-crawling software to efficiently source products using Python and increased product sourcing capabilities.
- Developed an online deal locator, catcher, detector, and checkout application using React and Python.

Software Developer

North American University

08/2016 - 01/2017 Houston TX

Achievements/Tasks

- Revised, modularized, and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Refactored UI codebase introducing React and Redux, built the codebase according to latest UI code practices, and added unit tests
 to reduce bug exposure.
- Built code running and grading framework with reporting capabilities, increasing efficiency of overall grading and reporting processes.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Science, Software Engineering

North American University

09/2016 - 05/2019

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Al Face Recognition And Detection Web Application (09/2020 - 12/2021)

- Face detection and face recognition application utilizing AI REST APIs.
- Fully designed and developed face detection and face recognition web application with AI training capabilities to persist face data in order to recognize previously detected human faces.
- Utilized React.js with HTML5/CSS for front-end and PostgreSQL, Node.js and Express.js for back-end.

Travel Guide (10/2018 - 12/2018)

- Open Source Project run by community of developers.
- Assisted in react performance optimization changes by optimizing state management and memoization techniques.
- Increased efficiency listing pages by utilizing react-window tool to optimize render capacity.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

OCA Certified Associate - JAVA SE Programmer (11/2018 - Present)

Gold Medal in National Computer Project Competition of Turkmenistan (04/2010 - Present)

Page 2 of 2